Sebastian Grubb

• New York, United States

■ Nationality: American, British and French

github.com/sg3510 in linkedin.com/in/sebastiangrubb

Summary

Product leader and founder with 10+ years of experience building products from 0-to-1 at VC-backed startups and scaling them to over 1B users at Google. Strong background in shipping highly technical, AI/ML-centric products, with strong experience in LLM applications, recommender systems and biometric models.

Experience

Raised \$3.7M from top investors including Race Capital, DCM and Pantera • Interviewed, hired and led a team of 6 (CTO, 3 software engineers, head of product and a customer success manager) in shipping revenue generating products.

Amino (AI powered food logging app - amino.fit 9)

- Launched Amino with the goal of being the most accurate AI food logging app. Amino differentiated itself by leveraging LLMs and RAG with food databases for superior calorie estimates over competing LLM-only apps.
- Led technical development (1500+ commits), design (hired and led UX) and marketing/growth. Grew to **5000+** users by leveraging various growth channels including social media influencers, organic marketing and paid ads.

Hedge Protocol (Collateralized lending platform)

- Launched a collateralized lending platform for digital assets on the Solana network that offered innovative one-time fee interest-free loans. Gained initial traction and investor interest by winning Solana 2021 hackathon.
- Grew platform to \$15m AUM and \$500k ARR with 2500+ users in our first year exclusively through unpaid channels including organic growth and cross-company partnerships.

Google (Android & Pixel)

Product Manager

Mountain View, US

2016 - 2021

Pixel Biometrics

- Launched Pixel 6's flagship under-display fingerprint sensor, enabling a seamless auth flow across Pixel (previous fingerprint sensor was on back). Convinced 100% of top banking apps to support the passwordless flow by demonstrating improved security.
- Led the ML team in building a faster, more secure and fair biometric model by spearheading a new data collection effort resulting in 5% lower false acceptance rate. This was a key factor in the launch of the new sensor.
- Redesigned all the Android flows to take into account a sensor in middle of the display.

Android Framework

- Improved Android app quality and privacy by launching new storage and media APIs, impacting over 70% of all Android apps. Storage was one of the most misused APIs and needed a full overhaul to allow apps to import user files.
- Launched new Android File Picker and led redesign of Google Photos photo picker API.
- Introduced new APIs at Google I/O 2019. •

Android Metrics

- Led Android to be a more data-centric org by setting up an effort to log much more UI usage in Android N, due to previously underlogging UI usage.
- Changed how settings, quick settings and notifications worked in Android O by convincing UX based on the new data.
- ullet Made Android more mass market friendly by removing the crash dialog in Android P. ullet

Emojis

- Spearheaded an industry-wide initiative to make emoji display more consistent across platforms by working with Apple, Twitter, Facebook and Samsung Notable example was ensuring the gun emoji was a toy on all platforms to avoid confusion •.
- Enforced emoji consistency between various Android OEMs.
- Author of multiple emojis including crutch emoji and co-author of transgender flag emoji •.

Google (YouTube Analytics) Associate Product Manager Zürich, CH

- Launched watch time as main metric (as opposed to views) to incentivise creation of longer content.
- Launched demographics reporting and ad rates based on largest YouTube partners feedback.

Ally Smart Care (Home Automation Startup)

2014 - 2015 *London, UK*

- Developed from scratch a sound detection neural net to classify common household sounds (gas stove on, fridge beeping, broken windows, baby crying etc) by hand picking features and designing the model architecture.
- Optimized neural network to run on lightweight hardware like Raspberry Pi via weight pruning.
- Got production ready demo ready in 3 months and presented it to YC for our CEO's pitch.

ARM Holdings plc 2013

Product Management Intern &

 $Cambridge,\ UK$

• Proposed new features for ARM processors to improve their feature offering for automative and industrial sectors.

ARM Holdings plc

2012

Engineering Intern

Cambridge, UK

• Wrote a VHDL interpreter in Perl to convert 8-bit architecture components to 16 or 32 bit architecture components.

Education

Imperial College London

2010 - 2014

M.Eng Electrical & Electronic Engineering (First Class Honours)

London, UK

• <u>Masters Thesis</u>: Active Sample Selection for Matrix Completion \mathfrak{G} | <u>Supervisor</u>: Moez Draief Authored a new active sampling method called Clustered Knowledge Search to improve ranking/recommender systems performance by identifying the most informative samples to query. Ranked in top 10% of final year projects.

- Scholarships & Awards: UKESF (UK Electronics Skill Foundation) scholarship, Maurice Hancock Award
- <u>Modules included</u>: Mathematics for Signal Processing, Advanced Signal Processing, Probability and Stochastic Processes, Optimisation, Machine Learning for Computer Vision, Probabilistic Inference

Skills

Technical Skills (ranked by experience)

- Programming Languages: Rust, Typescript, Python, MATLAB, C, SQL, ARM Assembly, Ruby, R, Perl
- Technologies: React, React Native, Supabase, RabbitMQ, Vercel, LLM APIs (OpenAI, Gemini, Claude)

Languages

• French (native) • English (native) • German (conversational)

Interests

- Keep various coding side projects with latest one being a Game Boy ROM disassembly interpreter.
- \bullet Avid interest in health & fitness including personal metric tracking & biohacking.
- \bullet Regular cyclist, participated in 2019 SF to LA AIDS/LifeCycle ride & raised \$5000 for charity.